Inventory of the Robert Paul Carlson Papers 1953-2007
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Robert Paul Carlson Papers 1953-20071960-1990
Special Collections Research Center
00/05/UA 5.106
0.40
This collection contains news clippings, correspondence, and photographs collected by Robert Paul Carlson, William and Mary class of 1966, from 1953-2007. The bulk of the material is made up of news clippings about Carlson's involvement with preserving the history of Maine Township in Park Ridge, Illinois, where he taught Social Studies for 50 years. Also included in the papers are two DVDs, including one from a 2007 message by New York Senator Hillary Clinton about Carlson, her former high school teacher, being inducted into the Maine Township's Wall of Honor. The other DVD features two 2005 news clips from ABC 7 and WTTW in Chicago, Illinois about Carlson teaching for almost 50 years at Maine East High School.
Carlson, Robert Paul arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from Gift of Donald Buchanan. on 08/06/2009.
Biographical Note
Robert Paul Carlson was a member of the College of William and Mary class of 1966. He was a teacher at Main East High School in Park Ridge, Illinois, where he taught for 50 years.Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Robert Paul Carlson.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains news clippings, correspondence, and photographs collected by Robert Paul Carlson, William and Mary class of 1966, from 1953-2007. The bulk of the material is made up of news clippings about Carlson's involvement with preserving the history of Maine Township in Park Ridge, Illinois, where he taught Social Studies for 50 years. Also included in the papers are two DVDs, including one from a 2007 message by New York Senator Hillary Clinton about Carlson, her former high school teacher, being inducted into the Maine Township's Wall of Honor. The other DVD features two 2005 news clips from ABC 7 and WTTW in Chicago, Illinois about Carlson teaching for almost 50 years at Maine East High School.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs
Topical Term:
Maine East High School (Park Ridge, Ill.); Maine Township (Ill.)--History--20th century.; Park Ridge (Ill.)--History--20th century.; Teachers
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id64193 (Box 1)
  - Introduction, Nomination for Maine Wall of Fame, 2006; id64321 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Saving Maine Township High School East, 1968-1970; id64322 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History of Maine Township High School, 1995; id64323 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mainites in Motion (Cold War Current Events Club), 1961-1964; id64324 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Margaret Lowery Memorial Fund Committee, 1973; id64325 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Veterans' Memorial Stadium, Veterans' Day and Memorial Day Rememberances, undated; id64326 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Maine Historical Society, Carlson Sponsorship, 1973; id64327 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Social Science Department Award Presentation, 1973-1976; id64328 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - State Capital Trip, undated; id64329 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Maine High Assembly, undated; id64330 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Erling Lunde, Honorary Membership in Maine Historical Society, 1972; id64331 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tedis Zierins (Latvian), undated; id64332 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Maine Historical Society, Cherry Pie Festival, 1971-2005; id64333 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Park Ridge Historical Society, 1973-1985; id64334 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Apollo Chorus, undated; id64335 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Association of Maine Alumni, undated; id64336 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Maine Centennial, 2002; id64337 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Social Science Club, 2004-2005; id64338 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Public Education, Community College, undated; id64339 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Thacker Junior High School, undated; id64340 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Study of Douglas McArthur, undated; id64341 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Honorary Degree from Ripon College, 1996; id64342 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Articles Featuring Paul Carlson, 1962-1968; id64343 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Who's Who Among America's Teachers, 1998; id64344 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - White House Letters, Hillary Clinton, 1994-1996; id64345 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - TRI-M: Modern Music Masters, 1952-1980; id64346 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondences, 1962-2001; id64347 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondences with Students, 1968-1999; id64348 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Articles on Retirement, 2006; id64349 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Maine Wall of Fame Nomination Letters, 2006; id64350 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Poem, "All in the State of Mind", undated; id64351 (Box 1, Folder 31)